Finding Aid for James Maxwell Mudge papers, 1951-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
James Maxwell Mudge papers 1951-1970
Mudge, James Maxwell, 1914-1970.
1.2 linear feet.
852015 Aa 2
Michigan newspaperman; correspondence and clippings of articles and columns.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by James M. Mudge (donor no. 4502 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
James M. Mudge was a newspaper reporter and columnist for the Grand Rapids Herald. He later became bureau chief for the Detroit Free Press, and press aide to Congressmen Gerald R. Ford and Guy Vander Jagt.
The collection consists primarily of clippings of newspaper articles and columns. In addition there is a scattering of correspondence, certificates, and drafts of speeches. Many of the articles relate to Detroit Mayor Jerome Cavanagh, especially his campaign for U.S. Senate in 1966. Correspondents include: Robert Griffin, John B. Swainson and G. Mennen Williams.
Subjects:
Detroit free press.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Grand Rapids herald (1892); Journalists--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Mudge, James Maxwell, 1914-1970.; American newspapers--Michigan--Detroit.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1966.; Vander Jagt, Guy, 1931-2007.; American newspapers--Michigan--Grand Rapids.
Contributors:
Cavanagh, Jerome Patrick, 1928-1979.; Griffin, Robert P. (Robert Paul), 1923-; Swainson, John Burley, 1925-; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-
- Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence, 1959-1969 (Box 1)
  - Activities as press aide to Congressman Gerald Ford (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous subjects, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
- Clippings of newspaper articles and columns
  - Undated, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - 1951, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955 (Box 1)
  - 1956, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1957, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1958, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1961, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1962, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1963, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1965 (Box 1)
  - 1966, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1967, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1968 (Box 1)
  - 1969, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - "Around Here" columns (Grand Rapids Herald), undated, 7 folders (Box 2)
  - "Dateline Grand Rapids" columns (Detroit Free Press), undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Folder 1)